你在被监视着
You are being watched.
政府有一套秘密系统
The government has a secret system--
一台每时每刻都在监视你的机器
A machine that spies on you every hour of every day.
我会知道  因为它是我造的
I know because... I built it.
我设计这台机器是为了侦测恐怖活动
I designed the machine to detect acts of terror
但它却看到了一切
but it sees everything--
它看到了与普通人相关的暴力罪行
Violent crimes involving ordinary people.
像你一样的普通人
People like you.
而政府认为这些罪行无关紧要
Crimes the government considered irrelevant.
他们不肯作为  所以我决定插手
They wouldn't act, so I decided I would.
但我需要一个搭档
But I needed a partner--
一个有能力介入其中的人
Someone with the skills to intervene.
因为受到当局追捕  我们只能秘密合作
Hunted by the authorities, we work in secret.
你永远找不到我们
You will never find us.
不管你是被害人还是行凶者
But victim or perpetrator,
如果你的号码被列出来  我们就会找到你
If you're number's up, we'll find you.
疑犯追踪 第1季 第12集
Person of Interest S01E12 720p HDTV x264
咖啡要凉了哦  警探
Your coffee's getting cold, detective.
西装不错
Nice suit.
你终于找到我了
You finally found me.
我却没听到警笛
but I don't hear any sirens
你也没用枪指着我
or see you reaching for your gun.
我在找"不好意思害你中枪了"道歉卡
I looked for a "I'm sorry I got you shot" Card,
结果身上没有了
but they were all out.
我不知道斯诺会做出这种事
I had no idea what Snow was capable of...
他真的是想杀你
that he'd actually try to kill you.
为什么联系我  卡特
Why did you contact me, Carter?
我有一肚子问题
Got a lot of questions.
你甩掉了你的跟屁虫
Well, you managed to lose your tail.
干得不错
That's quite a feat.
那些中情局的小子花了不少时间
Those CIA boys spend a lot of time
学会如何隐匿踪迹
learning how to be invisible.
你觉得就斯诺一个人盯着我吗
Think Snow is my only problem?
还有连我都不知道的特工
Is there another agency following you
跟着你吗
that I'm not aware of?
你屁股后面跟着整个
You've got an entire NYPD
纽约警局的特别小组
task force looking for you.
我闯了两个红灯跑过来
Had to run two lights getting here
就为了躲开我自己同事的跟踪
just to make sure my own people weren't trailing me.
我是个警察  警察有警察的规矩
I'm a cop, which means I've got rules.
不能破坏的规矩
Rules that can't be broken.
但是...我还是想知道内情
But, um... I want to know more.
踏上这条路
Once you go down that road...
你就不能再回头了
There's no looking back.
你怎么得到的那些信息
How are you getting your information?
我只能告诉你  我们能知道有人有危机
All I can tell you is we hear about people in danger.
或是有人在制造危机
or people who are causing it.
为什么告诉我
Why me?
因为你的道德观指向正确的方向
Because your moral compass is pointed in the right direction.
因为我被你追烦了
Because I'm tired of you chasing me.
接下来怎么做
How does this work?
安卓娅・古特雷斯
Andrea Gutierrez?
青少年时期有过保密犯罪记录的民事诉讼律师
Civil litigation attorney with a sealed juvie record.
我要看她的档案  卡特
I need it unsealed, Carter.
我刚说过规矩
What did I just say about rules?
你有你的规矩
You have your rules...
也有机会救人
and you have the chance to save a life.
选择在你
It's your choice.
等你联系
I'll be in touch.
你看起来很担心  芬奇
You look worried, Finch.
你的裁缝搬出城了吗
Did your tailor move out of the city?
和卡特警探的早饭吃得怎么样
How was your breakfast meeting with detective Carter?
你都听到了
You heard her.
她想知道咱们的信息是从哪来
She wants to know how we get our information.
绝不能告诉她机器的事
She can never know about the machine.
我觉得就算说了她也不一定信
I doubt if she'd believe it if I told her.
她倒是同意了给我们看安卓娅・古特雷斯的档案
She did agree to get us Andrea Gutierrez's juvie file.
不错  这是个正确方向的开端
Well, that's a step in the right direction.
你还发现了这位律师什么信息
What else did you find out about our lawyer?
安卓娅・古特雷斯  在皇后区出生长大
Andrea Gutierrez, born and raised in Queens.
高中退学后接受了普教发展
Got her G.E.D. after dropping out of high school.
社区大学毕业后
Worked her way through community college,
在纽约州立大学和皇后学院法学院读书
Then SUNY New Paltz and Queens college law
学习民事诉讼
where she studied civil litigation.
她很有上进心
She's a scrapper.
野心勃勃
Ambitious.
一心想过更好的生活
Just trying to make a better life for herself.
是的  但更好的生活代价也很高
Yes, but a better life can be expensive.
她欠了五万美元的助学贷款
She owes $50,000 in student loans...
信用卡还透支了两万
And another $20,000 on her credit cards.
很大一笔债啊
That's a lot of debt.
也许她管错误的人借了钱
Maybe she borrowed money from the wrong person.
有可能  她在生意上也欠着钱
It's possible; she owes money on her business, too.
看这个
Hey, watch it.
最近她正在为那些
Apparently she's trying to carve out a niche for herself
愤恨的罪犯和前科犯辩护
by suing the state on behalf of inmates and ex-cons
为自己的事业打下基础
with grievances from their stay behind bars.
那她的情况如何
How's that working out for her?
零胜诉六败诉
She's 0-for-6.
估计她希望最近的案子能交上好运
I imagine she hopes her current case will be lucky number seven.
反对  法官大人
Objection, your honor.
这些证据之间有关联吗
Relevance of this testimony?
法官大人  我只是想证实
Your honor, I'm just trying to prove
我的委托人唯一的过失
my client's only wrongdoing
是没把他的公寓收拾干净
was not cleaning his apartment well enough.
这毒品很旧  上面都是灰
The drugs were old, dusty,
说明是金先生戒毒以前的
from the days before Mr. King was clean.
反对  古特雷斯女士这算是在举证吗
Objection. Is Ms. Gutierrez testifying now?
奥康纳法官  这个案子毫无根据
Judge O'connor, this case is baseless,
就像之前古特雷斯女士呈上庭的
just like every other ex-con nuisance case
所有令人厌恶的前科犯案子一样
ms. Gutierrez has brought before this court.
我们作为公诉人   要求一个公正的判决
And we, the state, ask you to treat it as such.
-得了吧你  -古特雷斯女士
- Give me a break. - Ms. Gutierrez.
十分抱歉  法官大人
I'm sorry, your honor.
我只是很难听进去公诉人的话
I just have a hard time taking the state seriously
因为他的领带实在太搞笑了
when it's wearing that tie.
休庭  等两位成熟点再继续审判
Let's adjourn while you two grow up.
请双方管照好自己的证人
Get your witnesses in order.
周五再次开庭审理
We'll reconvene on Friday.
我明天过来看你  我保证
I'll come see you tomorrow, I promise.
-你会带上雅各布吗  -当然
- And you'll bring Jacob? - You bet.
这样不对  安卓娅  我是说  我没...
This is so wrong. Andrea, I mean, I didn't...
我什么都没做
I didn't even do anything.
记住我说的话  不要和那些
Remember what I said about not communicating
法庭上的人说话  特伦斯
with anyone from the trial, Terrence?
他是...他是我的假释官
He's my-- he's my parole officer.
现在不行  他什么也不是
Not right now, he's not.
格鲁斯卡  我跟你说过那些毒品不是我的
Galuska, I told you those drugs weren't mine.
我是说  你还给我做过检测  为什么不相信我
I mean, you tested me, man. Why don't you believe me?
我只是尽我的职责  特伦斯
I just did my job, Terrence.
毒品在你家里  说明就是你的
Those drugs were in your place. That makes them yours.
你应该更小心
You should have been more careful.
感谢致电家庭事务部  我能为您做些什么
Thank you for calling dfs. How may I assist you?
拉巴超市的五香熏牛肉三明治
Pastrami from Zabar's?
-你肯定要使唤我了  -特伦斯・金的血检结果
- You must need something big. - Terrence King's blood test.
他被捕的时候假释官给他做过
His parole officer did one when he was arrested,
我要用它来证明他没在吸毒
and I need it to help me prove that he wasn't using.
-你向法庭提出申请了吗  -过去几周了  但...
- Did you put in a request? - Weeks ago, but...
我给你查查  小安
I'll look into it, Andi.
谢谢啦
Thank you.
你最好快走  老大来了
You better go. Boss lady's coming.
我以为你在午餐时间加班呢  克里斯
I thought you were working through lunch, Chris...
没想到是在开小差
Not entertaining visitors.
她就是来取个文件
She just came for a file.
你有相应的手续吗
Did you go through proper channels?
我有  格洛丽亚  我发誓
I did, Gloria, I swear.
但那些手续都太...太太慢了
But those channels are so freaking...Slow.
恭喜坡终于拿到了他的毕业文凭
All right, to Poe finally getting his diploma.
古特雷斯小姐回家了吗
Did ms. Gutierrez go home?
她和一些朋友在喝酒
She stopped for drinks with some friends.
我本来还担心你改主意了
I was worried you'd change your mind.
呵  暂时没有
Ha, not yet.
我拿到了安卓娅・古特雷斯的秘密档案
I've got your girl Andrea Gutierrez's juvie records.
典型的麻烦精  整个大学二年级麻烦不断
Teenage troublemaker, B&E her sophomore year,
还受到过一连串的盗窃起诉
and a string of larceny charges.
别挂  卡特
Hold on, carter.
-什么事  莱奈尔  -卡特有动作
- What is it, Lionel? - Carter's up to something.
你别顾头不顾腚
You need to watch your ass.
谢谢你这么关心我的腚  莱奈尔
I appreciate your concern about my ass, Lionel,
卡特警探的事我能自己处理好
But I can handle detective Carter.
我可告诉你  她在和什么人打电话
I'm telling you, she's talking to someone
鬼鬼祟祟压着声音
and keeping it on the down low,
她在调查什么事
Working something on her own.
我会留意
I'll keep that in mind.
还在吗  卡特
You still with me, Carter?
我还在
Uh, yeah, yeah, I'm still with you.
我们现在该怎么做
So what do we do now?
静观其变
We'll watch and wait.
卡特
And Carter?
谢谢
Thanks.
里瑟  我不确定把那两个警探
Mr. Reese, I'm not sure that keeping both of our detectives
都蒙在鼓里是不是个好办法
in the dark is the best course of action.
情况会变得很复杂
This could get really complicated.
他们都很宝贵
They're assets.
他们对彼此了解的越少就越安全
The less they know about each other, the safer they'll be.
现在  我更担心古特雷斯小姐
Right now, I'm more concerned with Ms. Gutierrez.
芬奇  有人在跟踪她
Finch, someone's tailing our girl.
除你以外的人吗
Someone other than you?
里瑟先生
Mr. Reese?
里瑟先生  你还好吗
Mr. Reese, are you all right?
现在可希望那枪伤
Yeah, wishing gunshot wounds...
能痊愈得更快些了
healed faster right about now.
袭击者在用合成类固醇
Assailant's into anabolic steroids.
古特雷斯小姐呢
Where's Ms. Gutierrez?
她现在很安全
She's safe for now.
但是看那个人的身手
But with the way that guy handled himself,
我不确定以后会如何
I don't know for how much longer.
密码无效
知道是谁想杀害律师小姐吗
Any guesses about who'd want to kill our attorney?
昨晚袭击她的人
The guy who tried to attack her last night
看起来坐过牢
looked like he'd done time.
可能是愤怒的前委托人
Could be, uh, angry former client?
别盯着看
Excuse me.
我们得拿到她的档案
Well, we need to get her files.
看看攻击者是不是她的委托人
See if the assailant is one of her clients.
缩小嫌疑犯范围
Narrow down our suspects.
什么事
Yes?
我尽快赶过去
I'll be there as soon as I can.
请半天假吗  芬奇
Half day, Finch?
盯紧古特雷斯小姐
Stay close to Ms. Gutierrez.
我马上回来
I'll be back soon.
你终于减头发了
You cut your hair...finally.
你也终于换眼镜了
Got new glasses. Finally.
我想在开始教训你的地下赌博行径前
I suppose you could use some rest before I lecture you
你可以抓紧时间休息一下
on the perils of underground gambling.
那太好了  我快四十八小时没睡了
That'd be great. I've been up almost 48 hours.
我的狱友打呼噜像火车过境一样
My cellmate snored like a freight train.
很高兴你回家了  威尔
Happy you're home, Will.
抱歉又让你帮我保释
Sorry you had to bail me out again.
不管怎样  你回来了就好
Well, it's good to have you back either way.
你怎么神不知鬼不觉地潜入我办公室
How'd you get into my office without anyone noticing?
行业秘密
Trade secret.
我要你帮我查出
I need you to help me to find out
在哪可以买到那个牌子的类固醇
where to buy that brand of steroid.
怎么  你要锻炼肌肉吗
What, you looking to beef up?
它属于昨晚和我打过一场的家伙
It belonged to a guy I had a run-in with last night.
他很有技巧
Skilled fighter.
我想找出他活跃的那个健身房
Looking to track down the gym where he juices up.
你有别的想法吗
Are you having second thoughts?
只是办公室里的眼线比较多
There's just a lot of prying eyes around this place.
你也开始疑神疑鬼了呀  卡特
You're getting paranoid, Carter.
那就意味着你的方向正确了
That's a step in the right direction.
你想起诉你的老板
So you want to sue your boss.
很好  我们完全可以代理这个案子
Wonderful, uh... we can absolutely do that.
你做什么工作
Um, what, uh... what type of work do you do?
挺复杂
Uh, it's um, complicated.
你是怎么听说我的呢
Okay. How did you hear about me?
一个法警说对国家有抱怨的前科犯
A bailiff said ex-cons with gripes against the state
是你的专长
is your specialty.
-这是个不良信息嘛  -当然不是
- Is that bad information? - Um, no, not at all.
我以为这个是干净的民事案件
It's just I thought you were a clear-cut civil case.
我一直在找的理想对象
The unicorn I've been looking for...
比如完美男人
like the perfect man.
对不起  我今天笨手笨脚
Sorry, I'm all thumbs today.
我经常这么干  我马上回来
I do it all the time. I'll be right back.
漂亮  里瑟先生  有信号了
Nicely done, Mr. Reese. I have a signal now.
你的约会如何
How was your appointment?
很有效果  谢谢关心
Quite productive, thank you.
好了
Here we go.
告诉我  你为什么想起诉你老板
So, tell me, why do you want to sue your boss?
我的工作环境
Well, my working conditions are, um...
很不安全
unsafe.
我滑到了  伤了背
I slipped and hurt my back.
-是在工作时发生的吗  -就在昨晚
- Did that happen on the job? - Just last night, actually.
里瑟先生  两个话筒都有声音了
Mr. Reese, I've got sound in both microphones, now.
正在接通她的硬盘
Connecting to her hard drive.
我会发一封病毒邮件
I sent an email with a virus
伪装成布卢明代尔百货的任选六折优惠券
promising 40% off any purchase at Bloomingdales.
她肯定会下载
She couldn't resist downloading it.
你老板是什么样的人
So, what's this boss of yours like?
控制欲强  鬼鬼祟祟
Very manipulative. Secretive.
我们有些私人恩怨
We've had some personality conflicts.
我猜他很富有
I take it he has a lot of money.
他是那种独来独往的富翁
He's, uh, one of those rich loner types.
如果他不是这么有钱  肯定会被人当成怪胎
Kind you'd call strange if he didn't have so much cash.
所以他的话  是很古怪
So, instead, he's, uh, eccentric.
这个案子会占用很多时间
Well, this case is going to rack up a lot of hours.
我可以预付费用
I can pay upfront.
那我可以开始了
Then I can start immediately.
不过要在下个预约之后
Well, after my next appointment.
我要迟到了
I'm, uh, running late.
我会打给你
I'll call you.
我很期待
I look forward to it.
爸爸
Daddy!
他来了
There he is.
克里斯帮了我一个大忙
Chris did me a big favor by picking him up
把他从寄养家庭接了过来
from the foster family's place.
爸爸  你什么时候回家
When are you coming home, daddy?
我不喜欢我的房间
I don't like my room.
安卓娅会帮我出去
Andrea's gonna get me out of here
比你想象的还要快
sooner than you know it, all right?
没错  小家伙
That's right, buddy.
雅各布  先去那边
Yeah, Jacob, why don't you go over there right now,
和克里斯玩一会怎么样
hang with Chris for a minute.
让我和安卓娅谈完
And let me finish talking with Andrea?
你拿到了血液测试报告吗
So, um, so did you get the blood test?
我拜托克里斯了  但就算我们拿到了
Chris is working on it, but even if we get it--
他们还是在我房间里发现了毒品
Right. They still found the drugs in my house.
也许我们可以让你在独立实验室做测试
Maybe we can get you tested at an independent lab
证明你的清白  这很可行
and prove that you were clean. It could help.
不管你需要什么  我都会做
Whatever you need, I'll do it.
我知道我不能付你钱
Look, I know I can't pay you
我也知道没什么希望  但是...
and I know that it's not looking good, but...
谢谢你
Thank you.
每个人都该有第二次机会
Everyone deserves a second chance.
你有发现了
You've found something.
品牌名是康复龙
Brand name's Anadrol.
是种在综合格斗健身房很流行的混合物
It's a popular compound found in some MMA gyms.
在纽约有三个健身房销售
Turned up in buy-and-busts at three gyms in the boroughs.
地址是什么
What are the locations?
你要保证不搞出乱子
I'll tell you only if I don't wind up
我就告诉你  明白吗
getting called to a crime scene, understood?
向你保证  警探
You have my word, detective.
看到袭击者了吗
Any sign of our assailant?
三个地点都没有
Third location, and still nothing.
可能昨晚的那位朋友
Could be our friend from last night
决定休息一天
decided to take the day off.
芬奇  我看到他了
Finch, I see him.
还记得我吗
Hey, you remember me?
小心
Look out!
里瑟  你还好吗
Reese, are you okay?
还好  但那家伙就没这么好了
Yes, but I can't say the same about the other guy.
看来我得食言了
So much for not dropping any bodies.
死者名叫阿隆索・加西亚
Our dearly departed hit man, Alonso Garcia,
有前科
was an ex-con.
他因二级过失杀人罪
He served three years at five points
在五点区服役三年
for second-degree manslaughter.
五点区  位于纽约曼哈顿南部  治安混乱
但安卓娅不是他的代理律师
But Andrea wasn't his representative.
那他们之间有什么联系
Then what's their connection?
特伦斯・金
Terrence King.
他们的假释官都是道米尼克・格鲁斯卡
They share a parole officer named Dominic Galuska.
对  我在法院见过他
Yeah, saw him at the courthouse.
也许我该去拜访一下格鲁斯卡先生
Maybe I should pay Mr. Galuska a visit,
看看这是不是单纯的巧合
see if this is more than just a coincidence.
我知道你想说什么
I know what you're gonna say.
我给了你地址  你跟我保证
I give you an address, and you promised me
不会出人命  结果呢
no one would get dead, and what happens?
这我要自辩一下  加西亚先生
In my defense, Mr. Garcia didn't look both ways
过马路前没有朝两边看
before crossing the street.
你怎么知道死者的名字
How did you know the dead guy's name?
我们还没确认他的身份
We couldn't find any I.D. on him.
在他的驾照上写着
It was on his driver's license.
你偷了死人的钱包
You stole a dead guy's wallet?
他昨晚想杀了安卓娅・古特雷斯
He tried to kill Andrea Gutierrez last night,
他还会再下杀手
and he was going to try again.
加西亚手头有多少钱  1万吗
Garcia had just under, what, 10 grand on him?
我猜是杀手赏金
My guess, it's a payoff for a hit.
谁想杀她
Who'd want to kill her?
正在查
I'm working on it.
我这个月没钱付给你  格鲁斯卡
I can't pay you this month, Galuska.
要是我收不到钱
If I don't get my cut,
我保证会找到一堆违反假释的地方
I bet I could find a dozen parole violations,
再把你扔进去
throw you back inside.
这是10%  行了吧
That's 10%, okay?
我给你这份工作的时候
When I got you this job,
说好要薪水的30%
our deal was 30% of your paycheck.
别想占我便宜  卢
Don't you cheap out on me, Lou.
道米尼克
Hey, Dominic!
我的钱呢
Where's my money?
你以为自己在跟谁说话
Who do you think you're talking to?
我想我在跟一个勒索假释犯
I thought I was talking to the guy who's shaking down
合法收入的人说话
his parolees for their legit pay.
看看能不能帮我
See if you can find me
找瓶酒过来  好吗
a bottle of booze in there, will you?
-谢了  -911  有什么紧急状况
- Thank you. - 911, state your emergency.
我叫道米尼克・格鲁斯卡
My name is Dominic Galuska,
我对自己和他人都是个祸害
and I may be a danger to myself and others.
旧阁楼
Wow, the old loft.
是啊  葬礼之后就没来过这儿了
Yeah, haven't been here since the funeral.
我想着你也许哪天会回来
I thought you might come back to it someday.
我把一些东西打包放到仓库了
I'm packing some stuff up to send to storage.
要是你对什么东西有兴趣  告诉我
If there's anything that you're interested in, let me know.
谢谢  你考虑留下吗
Thanks. You thinking about staying?
不  我在考虑卖掉这里
No, I'm thinking about selling the place.
一直不太喜欢这儿
Never really liked it much here.
他离婚后就搬来这里了
It's where he moved after the divorce.
看起来总是很大  很贵  很空
Always seemed too big... expensive...vacant.
他忙于工作
Well, he worked a lot.
我大概知道你的想法
Guess I can see how you might think that.
抱歉  我忘了问
Sorry, I forgot to ask--
保险生意怎么样
How's the insurance business going?
无聊依旧  谢谢
Boring as ever, thank you.
你有没有全部翻看过
Have you had a chance to go through everything?
原来我爸有点收藏癖
It turns out dad was a bit of a pack rat.
好像有一半是我的东西
It looks like half of it's mine.
项目企划  各种奖项  大学论文
Projects, awards, papers from school.
你一直是优秀学生
Well, you always were an outstanding student.
有没有想过完成住院医师实习期
Have you thought about finishing your residency?
不了  全世界到处是
No, got plenty of action
无国界医生组织  红十字会之类的活动
around the world with MSF, Red Cross.
感觉不到我在帮助别人
Didn't feel like I was helping people.
你是医生  你的工作就是帮助别人
You're a doctor. All you do is help people.
我只是在治疗既成事实的病症
I treat symptoms of the disease after the fact,
而不是根源
never the underlying cause.
我想要真正地帮助别人
I want to really help people.
我在想  你多像你父亲啊
I was just thinking how much you sound like your father.
是啊
Yeah.
我能说服你留下吗
Any chance I can convince you to stay?
抱歉
Sorry.
不要不告而别
Well, don't leave without saying good-bye.
不会的
I won't.
你陷害格鲁斯卡说他威胁
You framed Galuska for making a death threat
要杀了他手下的假释犯
against one of his parolees?
是你说需要证据
You said you needed evidence.
不是这种
Not like that.
卡特  如果你不想审问他
If you don't wanna interrogate him, Carter,
我很乐意代劳
I'd be happy to do it for you.
他已是笼中鸟了
He's already in the box.
很好  我们要查出他是否有同谋
Good, we need to find out if he's working with anyone.
看他有没有派别人去杀安卓娅
See if he's sent anyone else after Andrea.
我自己的工作自己会做  谢了
I know how to do my job, thank you.
不过我确实发现了格鲁斯卡有点问题
But I did find something interesting about Galuska.
他有几个假释犯被送回牢中
Several of his parolees that got sent back inside
一直在控诉是被他陷害
complained about him setting them up.
说格鲁斯卡仿造证据
Said Galuska planted evidence on them.
他怎么脱的身
What does he get out of it?
我去查查
I'm gonna find that out.
还有  能不能拜托你别再违法了
In the meantime, can you try not to break any more laws?
你好  莱奈尔  想我了吗
Hello, Lionel, miss me?
没错  想得头都痛
Yeah, like I miss a hangover.
-有个任务给你  -是卡特吗
- I've got a job for you. - This about Carter?
她还是表现得很诡异
Because she's still acting all hinky.
不是  我现在担心的不是卡特
No, it's not Carter I'm concerned about right now.
是别人
It's someone else.
好吧  什么任务
All right, what's this job?
"倾心"相亲网
约翰
John?
我们有约吗
Do we have an appointment?
没有  但我有个问题
No, but I have a question.
我刚被指定了一个新假释官
I was just assigned a new P.O.
他这人挺难搞
He's being difficult.
叫道米尼克・格鲁斯卡
His name's Dominic Galuska.
我认识这家伙  绝对的混蛋
I know that guy. Total jackass.
他总是搜查我的公寓
He keeps searching my apartment,
根本没什么东西  但他一来再来
and there's nothing to find, but he keeps coming back.
如果他再出现  打电话给我
If he shows up again, call me.
不管是白天晚上  我都会过去
I'll be there, anytime of the day or night.
当然是指工作时间
On the clock, of course.
那网站有用吗
How's that site working out for you?
我这行比较难找到合适的人
It's hard to find the right kind of guy in my line of work.
不可能吧  你那么有魅力  又聪明
That seems odd, because you're very attractive, smart...
我们打住吧  约翰
Let me stop you there, John.
我不跟委托人和前科犯约会
I don't date my clients or ex-cons.
试过  够了
Been there, done that.
你现在看到的是新版安卓娅
This is Andrea 2.0 you're looking at.
此外  我想你付钱
Plus, I need your money.
而且  我喜欢我的另一半
And I like my guys not quite so...
长得不要比我好看
better looking than me.
为什么要留在你从小长大的地方
Why did you stay in the town where you grew up?
为什么不重新开始
I mean, why not start fresh?
因为我不会逃避自我
Because I'm not running away from who I was.
我相信犯错不要紧
I was taught it's okay to make mistakes,
每个人都应该有第二次机会
and I believe everyone deserves a second chance.
威胁假释犯的生命  道米尼克
Threatening a parolee's life, Dominic?
这是个误会
This is some kind of misunderstanding.
景气不太好
Just a little depressed, huh?
工作不易做
You got a tough job.
依我看来  你是不太擅长
From what I'm seeing here, you're not very good at it.
你的重新犯罪率最高
You got the worst recidivism rate in your office.
上个月送进牢里的人数比我还多
Kicked more guys back inside last month than I did.
有些人说是被你陷害
Some were even saying they were set up.
警探  你知道罪犯的套话就是"我没干"
You know a criminal's motto, detective: "I didn't do it."
你从事的是公共服务工作  格鲁斯卡先生
You're doing a public service, Mr. Galuska.
活累  钱少
Hard work, crap pay.
所以你开好车这一点还挺奇怪
Which is why it's interesting you drive such a nice truck.
我阿姨几个月前去世了
My aunt passed away a couple of months ago.
给我留了点儿钱
Left me some money.
关你啥事儿
Why do you care?
有人受伤就关我事儿
I care when people get hurt.
比如你的假释犯  阿隆索・加西亚
Like your parolee, Alonso Garcia.
他今天下午被车撞死了
Guy got run over in red hook this afternoon.
他要乖点也不至于这样
Couldn't happen to a nicer guy.
你知道加西亚先生
Did you know Mr. Garcia
两天前企图谋杀安卓娅・古特雷斯吗
Tried to kill Andrea Gutierrez two nights ago?
我说过了  他要乖点也不至于这样了
Like I said, couldn't happen to a nicer guy.
无论如何  我也想不明白为什么
I can't, for the life of me, figure out what kind of grudge
阿隆索・加西亚会怨恨古特雷斯小姐  你呢
Alonso Garcia would have against Ms. Gutierrez, can you?
我想我现在需要律师了
I think I'm ready for my lawyer now.
没错
Yeah.
如何
How'd it go?
不好意思  我这回考了个零鸭蛋
I'm sorry, got a big goose egg on this one.
格鲁斯卡被放了
Galuska walked.
没事  你做得很好 卡特
Oh, no, you did great, Carter.
你们俩还在聊天的时候
Because while you two were having a chat,
我进了他的公寓
I got into his apartment,
借走了他的电脑
Borrowed his computer.
你擅闯他的公寓
You broke into his apartment?
你说你不能干违法的勾当
You said you couldn't do anything illegal.
你可没说我不能
You didn't say anything about me.
格先生该学会用生日之外的密码
Mr. Galuska should know better than to protect
来保护他的重要文件
His important files with his birth date.
对于一个年薪不超过万的人来说
That's a hell of a lot of money in the bank for a man
这钱可有点多啊
Who makes less than 50 grand a year.
每笔存款时间都吻合
Each deposit coincides with when he sent
他的假释人被送回监狱的时间
One of his parolees back to prison.
他肯定是在从哪里拿回扣
He's getting kickbacks from somewhere or someone.
监狱是个大生意
Prisons are big business.
囚犯越多  经费越多
The more inmates, the more funding.
格先生三天前从他户头里
Mr. Galuska took out exactly $9,900
取了九千九
From his savings account three days ago.
任何超过一万的交易都会报备国税局
Anything over 10,000 gets flagged by the IRS.
他付阿隆索・加西亚钱去刺杀安卓娅
He paid Alonso Garcia to kill Andrea.
这还不是唯一的取现
That's not the only withdrawal.
还有一样的一笔钱也取现了
There's another one in the same amount
就在昨晚
Just last night.
也就是说
That means--
他雇了其他人来完成这事
He hired someone else to finish the job.
约翰
John!
约翰  这是怎么回事
John, what is going on?
我是不需要你的服务了  安卓娅
I don't need your services anymore, Andrea.
但是我觉得你需要我的服务
But I think you're gonna need mine.
里瑟先生  你到安全屋了吗
Mr. Reese, are you at the safe house yet?
正在路上
Heading there now.
够了  这到底是怎么回事
Okay, what the hell?!
你有危险  安卓娅
You're in danger, Andrea.
这还要你说  拿枪那个人是谁
Um, you think? Who was the guy with the gun,
你又是谁  因为你刚刚偷袭他的时候
And who are you, because your back
你的背明明没问题
Seemed just fine when you went ninja on that guy.
我就像你  给别人第二次机会
I'm like you--I give people second chances.
那你从没进过监狱
So you were never in jail?
在这个国家没有
Not in this country.
不好意思
Excuse me.
里瑟先生
Mr. Reese?
我刚刚看到一份逮捕报告
An arrest report just came in
是你在法律图书馆逮住的那个人
For the gentleman you apprehended in the law library.
他名叫温德尔・兰茨
His name is Wendell Lentz,
而且我刚确认了他的假释官也是格鲁斯卡
And I've confirmed that he's one of Dominic Galuska's parolees.
好  我们得确保格鲁斯卡
Okay, we need to make sure Galuska doesn't have any more
不再派杀手找安卓娅麻烦
Killers out there looking for Andrea.
我做了什么
What did I do?
格鲁斯卡靠陷害前科犯赚钱
Galuska's getting money from someone to set up his ex-cons
然后把他们踢回监狱
And send them back to prison.
你那个特伦斯的案子彻底捅了马蜂窝
You kicked a hornet's nest with Terrence's case.
可能是格鲁斯卡在他家放了那些毒品
Galuska may have planted those drugs in his home.
我的天
Oh, my god.
这么说特伦斯真是无辜的
That means Terrence is actually innocent.
你都不确定
You weren't sure?
我也想这么想
I wanted to be.
特伦斯被逮捕那晚所做的药检
Terrence was given a drug test the night he was arrested,
结果是阴性
And it came back negative.
格鲁斯卡和劳教部门
Galuska and the Department of Corrections
很方便就能做手脚
Conveniently misplaced it.
我从没见过那份报告
I never got a copy of the report.
于是你再挖  结果发现了
A little more digging, you'd also have found
所有针对他的投诉
All the complaints filed against him.
假释人指控格鲁斯卡陷害他们
Parolees who said Galuska set them up.
-我得告诉特伦斯  -你留在这
- I need to tell Terrence. - You need to stay here
等我先找出他又雇了谁来杀你
Until I find out who else he may have hired to kill you
并且格鲁斯卡在为谁干活再说
And who galuska's working for.
呆在这  锁好门
Stay here, lock the doors,
谁来都不要开
And don't open them for anyone.
我想你该知道怎么用这个吧
I take it you know how to use this?
你要是跟我长在一个地方  就知道怎么保护自己
You grow up where I did, you know how to handle yourself.
你现在甩尾的功夫是越来越厉害了
You're getting better at ditching your tail.
没准你找到知法犯法的窍门了
Maybe you got a knack for breaking the law.
我又去查了遍格鲁斯卡的文件
I've been going back through Galuska's files
发现了个规律
And found a pattern.
去年  所有他抓到的假释人
In the past year, all the parolees
都是单亲
He's busted were single parents.
也就是说他们的子女要进收养机构
Which means their kids end up in foster care.
格鲁斯卡他不是在从假释人身上挣钱
Galuska wasn't getting paid for the parolees.
他在靠卖他们的小孩赚钱
He was getting paid for their kids.
每个小孩每个月能有800块
Each child is worth about 800 bucks a month.
格鲁斯卡肯定和家庭事务部的人合伙
Galuska's gotta be working with someone at DFS.
家庭事务部可是个大部门
Well, DFS is a big agency.
我得去会会金赛那俩口子了
I'm gonna have a talk with Mary and Paul Kinsey--
照顾特伦斯儿子的那个寄宿家庭双亲
The foster parents looking after Terrence King's kid.
你很在行  卡特
You're good at this, Carter.
这是我的工作
It's my job.
而且我还不用对人开枪就能办事
And I didn't even have to shoot anyone to do it.
我只有几个问题  金赛先生和夫人
I just have a few questions, Mr. and Mrs. Kinsey.
我保证不会花你们太多时间
I promise not to take up too much of your time.
出什么事了
Something wrong?
我是真希望没事  夫人
I certainly hope not, Ma'am.
这里说你们有六个寄养在你们家的孩子
I see here you have six foster children under you care.
-是不是这样  -是的  没错
- Is that still correct? - It is, yes.
好  那么  雅各布・金是不是当中一个
Okay, and, uh, Jacob King is one of those kids?
这跟雅各布有关么
This is about jacob?
他很想他爸爸  但是他适应得很好
He misses his dad, but... He's adjusting just fine.
你俩当中有人
Do you, either of you,
认识一个叫道米尼克・格鲁斯卡的人吗
Know a man named Dominic Galuska?
不认识  谁啊
No, who's that?
那格洛丽亚・科普兰呢
What about Gloria Copeland?
她是家庭事务部的寄养安排主管
She's the head of foster placement at DFS.
你们名下那六个孩子都睡哪
Where do all six of the children that are under your care sleep?
因为在我看来
Because it looks to me...
你们住的是一室一厅的公寓
You live in a one-bedroom apartment.
哪来那么多空间住六个小孩两个大人
Not much space for six kids and two adults.
得了  你们俩赶紧给我从实招来
Okay, you tell me the truth now, or I arrest both of you
不然我就按阻挠刑事案件调查罪名逮捕你们
For interfering with a criminal investigation.
雅各布是唯一一个还跟我们住一起的孩子
Jacob's the only child living with us right now.
那名单上的其他人  丽贝卡・强森  特里・怀特
So the others on the list, Rebecca Johnson, Trey White...
丽贝卡几个月前就逃走了
Rebecca ran away months ago.
特里・怀特和其他人  他们
Trey White and the other children, they...
不存在
The others don't exist.
但我敢说你们还拿着钱
But I bet you're still getting paid for all of them.
够了  保罗
Enough, Paul.
给我闭嘴
You shut your mouth.
格鲁斯卡一个人玩不出这种花样
Galuska's not smart enough to pull this off on his own.
所以他肯定有个家庭事务部的内应
So he had to have a contact at DFS,
而你们要告诉我那人是谁
And you are going to tell me who that person is.
我们要律师
We want a lawyer.
还要打电话
And our phone call.
哪都别去
Don't go anywhere.
谁啊
Who is this?
你认识我的  警探
You know who, Detective.
我要你让金赛夫妇去打电话
I want you to give the Kinseys their phone call.
你这是在干扰我办案
You are interrupting me
我还在审讯中
In the middle of an interrogation.
在我看来已经审讯结束了
Sounded like the end of an interrogation to me.
他们都要叫律师了
They asked for their lawyer.
你怎么会知道
How would you know that?
你窃听我电话了
Are you bugging my phone?
我要你让金赛夫妇去打电话
I want you to give the Kinseys their phone call.
除非我问出那内应  否则免谈
Not until I find out who their contact at DFS is.
我们认为这已经有答案了  警探
We think we already know who that person is, Detective.
我们查了格鲁斯卡逮捕的最后六个人
We've checked the DFS filings for the last six parolees
在家庭事务部的文件记录
That Galuska busted.
所有的六份文件都是同一个署名
The signatures on all six belong to one woman:
格洛丽亚・科普兰
Gloria Copeland.
行啊  但这不足以作为证据逮捕她
Yeah, but that's not enough evidence to arrest her.
家庭事务部就是个巨型文件堆
DFS is a mountain of paperwork.
要理清楚得花几个月的时间
It'd take months to sort through it all,
并且如果金赛夫妇通知了她
And if the Kinseys tip her off,
科普兰肯定会销毁证据
Copeland's only gonna destroy the evidence.
这正是我们所希望的
That's exactly what we want her to do.
如果我们要合作  警探
If we're gonna work together, detective,
还是需要彼此间留点信任
A little bit of trust is in order.
芬奇  进去了吗
Finch, are you in?
刚进
Just.
你得抓紧了
Well, you need to move fast.
多谢你的提醒  里瑟先生
Thanks for that newsflash, mr. Reese.
我现在动作慢慢吞吞地
Here I was planning to move at a sloth-like pace
正指望着自己被逮着呢
and get myself captured.
扫描仪装好了  里瑟先生
The scanner's installed, mr. Reese.
这样够快了吗
Was that fast enough for you?
喂
Hello?
这是一个从布鲁克林拘留所
Will you accept a collect call
付费电话  你愿意接吗
from metropolitan detention center, Brooklyn,
来电人是  特伦斯
On behalf of Terrence?
是的  当然
Yes, of course.
特伦斯  怎么了
Terrence, what's wrong?
他们明天要把我转到阿提卡监狱
They're moving me to Attica tomorrow.
什么
What?!
-为什么  -我不知道
- Why? - I don't know.
但听着  那里不是拘留所
But look, that's not a detention facility.
是最高级别的监狱
That's maximum security...
我去了那里就死定了
And I can't make it in there.
听着  我会提交一份禁令叫停转监
Look, I'm just gonna file an injunction to stop the transfer.
我们需要找人帮忙说服法官
We're gonna need some help convincing a judge.
好吧
Okay, all right.
我会想办法解决  好吗  特
I'm gonna take care of this, okay, T?
好
Right.
我们的看法没错
We were right.
金赛夫妇肯定告诉了格洛丽亚・科普兰
The Kinseys must have contacted Gloria Copeland.
她开始销毁文件了
She's begun shredding the documents.
我收到了扫描件
I'm getting the scans now.
看来每次道米尼克・格鲁斯卡
Looks like every time Dominic Galuska
把他的一个假释犯送回监狱
Sends one of his parolees back to prison,
科普兰女士就利用家庭寄养的程序
Ms. Copeland uses the foster care paperwork
来隐藏她捏造的孩子
To hide the kids she's fabricated.
她让假释犯看起来
She makes it look like the parolees
有比实际更多的孩子
Have more kids than they actually do.
这么一来肯定能每月诈取25万
This scam must be worth upwards of $1/4 million a month.
我们有麻烦了  芬奇
We got a problem then, Finch.
格洛丽亚・科普兰提前下班了
Gloria Copeland left work early.
销毁文件的那个人不是她
She isn't the one shredding the documents.
格鲁斯卡在家庭事务部的内线另有其人
Galuska's got a different contact at DFS.
安卓娅  你在这里做什么
Andrea, wh--what are you doing here?
特伦斯明早要被转去阿提卡监狱
Terrence is being transferred to attica in the morning.
你想要我怎么做
Um, what do you want me to do about it?
打给他案子的办事员  克里斯
Call his case worker, Chris.
告诉她联系签那道文件的法官
Tell her to contact the judge who made the order.
转监对孩子不利
The transfer's not in the best interest of the child.
不行
I can't do that.
你怎么了  为什么不行
What's wrong with you? Why not?
因为是我让法官下令转监的
Because I'm the one that asked the judge to move him.
你和格鲁斯卡是一伙的
You're working with Galuska.
你知道这事可惜在哪里吗  小安
You know the shame of it, Andi?
到头来发现其实你的确是个不错的律师
Turns out you're actually a pretty good lawyer.
只是没人会知道了
Not that anyone's ever gonna know it.
里瑟先生  我在比对格洛丽亚・科普兰
Mr. Reese, I'm running a handwriting analysis
和克里斯・斯科拉的签名
On the signatures of Gloria Copeland and Chris Scollard.
他们两个人名字里的R完全一致
The rs in both names are identical.
他伪造了她的签名
He forged her signature.
格洛丽亚・科普兰完全不知道真相
Gloria Copeland had no idea what was going on.
你为什么这么做  克里斯
Why would you do this, Chris?
你怎么能背叛那些家庭
How could you betray all those families?
那些孩子在寄养家庭
Those kids were better off with their foster families
比在那些罪犯父母身边更好
Than they ever were with their convict parents.
特伦斯的儿子让他有理由远离毒品
Terrence's son gave him a reason to stay clean.
他有工作和他的生活
He got a job, a life.
你有什么资格拆散他们的家庭
Who are you to take away their chance at being a family?
我挺佩服你的同情心
I admire that bleeding heart of yours.
我宁愿同情心泛滥也不要铁石心肠
I'd rather it bleed than stop beating altogether.
他跑了
He's getting away.
他跑不了
No, he's not.
纽约警察  转过身去
NYPD. Turn around.
扔下枪
Drop your weapon.
扔掉
Drop it!
过来  小家伙
Whoa, come here, buddy.
我好想你  伙计
Oh, I missed you, man.
我想死你了
I missed you so much.
我马上回来
Um, I'll be right back.
好
Yeah, yeah.
我读了你的结案陈词
I read about your settlement with the state.
冤狱  诽谤
Wrongful imprisonment, defamation of character--
还有侵犯公民权
Don't forget violation of civil rights
和恶意起诉
And malicious prosecution.
你得到了一千万中的30%  不赖
You get 30% of $10 million. Not bad.
也许你可以不用再溜进纽约大学的图书馆了
Maybe you can stop sneaking into NYU's library.
我想我还是先买双新鞋子吧
I think I'm gonna start with a new pair of shoes.
再说  我喜欢那里
Besides, I like it in there.
那里气氛很棒
Has a good vibe.
你都差点在那里被杀
Even after you almost go killed?
有你和你复杂的工作救我了嘛
Well, I had you and your complicated job to save me.
你没想过找一份风险小点的工作吗
You ever think of having a less hazardous profession
比如登山或摔跤啥的
Like mountain climbing or bear wrestling?
我是说  为你不认识的人冒生命危险
I mean, is it really worth risking your life
真的值得吗
For people you don't know?
不是只有你相信人有第二次机会
You're not the only one who believes in second chances.
谢谢你
Thank you.
哈罗德叔叔
Hey, uncle harold.
你打电话来时  我以为你又要走了
When you called, I assumed it was going to be good-bye again.
不  我不准备卖房子了
No, I'm not gonna sell the place.
反正现在不会
Not right away, anyway.
你又开始住院实习了吗
Are you taking up your residency again?
不
No.
我不想再帮人缝缝补补了
I'm done patching people up,
我想更了解我父亲
And I wanna find out more about my dad.
看看这个
Look at this.
这是你考进医学院那天
This was the day you got into med school.
他多么为你骄傲
He was so proud of you.
一直是这样
Always was.
我翻他的东西时
Going through his things,
才发现我有多不了解他
I realize how little I really knew him.
我觉得大多数父亲对儿子来说都很神秘
I think most fathers are a mystery to their sons.
大多数儿子都没机会
Well, most sons don't have the advantage
看到未经授权的自传
Of reading the unauthorized biography.
或是这些
Or all this.
这是他把半个公司留给我时
It's from the audit his lawyers did
他的律师们做的审计
When he left me his half of the company.
而大多我都搞不明白
Now, most of it I don't understand.
我超不擅长电脑  就像你  是吗
I get lost when it comes to computers, like you, right?
是啊
Right.
但有些事情我很清楚
But, there are some things I do understand.
事情互相矛盾
Inconsistencies like... Did you know
你知道他的公司关闭了七年之久吗
That he shut down IFT for nearly seven years?
是  我知道他缩减了规模
Yes, I knew that he downsized a bit.
他付了所有员工一笔遣散金
Well, he gave all his employees severance
还给他们寄了包裹
And sent them packing.
他为什么要这么做
Why would he do that?
还有  看这个  不论他在做什么
And, look, whatever it was that he was working on,
他以一美元的价格卖给了政府
He sold it to the government for a dollar.
也就是说这件东西不是一文不值
So that means it was either something worthless...
就是无价之宝
Or priceless.
他有和你说起过吗
Did he ever talk to you about it?
我是说  你是他最好的朋友
I mean, you were his closest friend.
没有  他从没说过
No, he never did.
你去哪了  芬奇
Where have you been, Finch?
我今天不回办公室了
I won't be back in the office today.
也许你今天该好好休息下
Maybe you should take the rest of the day off as well.
你想和我聊聊吗
You want to talk about it?
不太想
Not particularly.
但你得承认  你有心事
But you admit there is something going on,
你在担心什么事
Something that you're worried about.
这让我很担心你
That makes me worried.
你不用担心我  里瑟先生
Well, you needn't, mr. Reese.
我希望你明白  有些事情
I hope you understand that there are certain things
我不能告诉你
That I can't tell you.
我完全明白  芬奇
Oh, I understand completely, Finch.
怎么样了  莱奈尔
How's it going, lionel?
我在忙你给我的新任务呢
I'm on that new assignment you gave me.
我得说  你好歹给报销车费啊
I gotta say, I should at least be getting cab fare for this.
这项工作很快就结束吗
This job ending any time soon?
只要我找到我要的答案
As soon as I get some answers.
疑犯追踪 第1季 第12集
Person of Interest S01E12 720p HDTV x264
-= YYeTs人人字幕 =-